export const Questions = [
  {
    prompt: "Q.1 What is ReactJS?",
    optionA: "A) Server-side Framework",
    optionB: "B) User-interface framework",
    optionC: "C) A Library for building interaction interfaces",
    optionD: "D) None of the Above",
    answer: "optionC",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.2 Which of the following is must for the API in React.js?",
    optionA: "A) SetinitialComponent",
    optionB: "B) renderComponent",
    optionC: "C) render",
    optionD: "D) All of the above",
    answer: "optionB",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.3 Which of this is not a javascript framework?",
    optionA: "A) React",
    optionB: "B) Angular",
    optionC: "C) Vue",
    optionD: "D) Java",
    answer: "optionD",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.4 In React, what is the purpose of state?",
    optionA: "A) To store and manage data that can change over time",
    optionB: "B) To define the structure of a component",
    optionC: "C) To handle HTTP requests",
    optionD: "D) To handle user events like button clicks",
    answer: "optionA",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.5 What does JSX stand for?",
    optionA: "A) JavaScript XML",
    optionB: "B) Java Syntax Extension",
    optionC: "C) JSON XML",
    optionD: "D) JSX has no abbreviation",
    answer: "optionA",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.6 Which of the following is the entry point for a React application?",
    optionA: "A) index.js",
    optionB: "B) app.js",
    optionC: "C) main.js",
    optionD: "D) entry.js",
    answer: "optionA",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.7 In React, what is the purpose of the render() method?",
    optionA: "A) To trigger a component's initial rendering",
    optionB: "B) To update the component's state",
    optionC: "C) To render the component's children elements",
    optionD: "D) To define the component's constructor",
    answer: "optionC",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.8 How can you pass data from a parent component to a child component in React?",
    optionA: "A) By using the this.props object",
    optionB: "B) By using the this.state object",
    optionC: "C) By using the this.data object",
    optionD: "D) By using the this.child object",
    answer: "optionA",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.9 In React, what is the purpose of the `setState()` method?",
    optionA: "A) To update the component's state and trigger a re-render",
    optionB: "B) To set initial props for a component",
    optionC: "C) To update the component's props",
    optionD: "D) To update the component's context",
    answer: "optionA",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.10 Which lifecycle method is called after a component's render method has been executed?",
    optionA: "A) `componentDidUpdate`",
    optionB: "B) `componentWillMount`",
    optionC: "C) `componentDidMount`",
    optionD: "D) `componentWillUpdate`",
    answer: "optionC",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.11 Which React hook is used to add state and other React features to a functional component?",
    optionA: "A) `useEffect`",
    optionB: "B) `useState`",
    optionC: "C) `useReducer`",
    optionD: "D) `useContext`",
    answer: "optionB",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.12 Which React hook is used for handling side effects, such as fetching data or subscribing to events?",
    optionA: "A) `useContext`",
    optionB: "B) `useReducer`",
    optionC: "C) `useEffect`",
    optionD: "D) `useState`",
    answer: "optionC",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.13 What is the purpose of React Fragments?",
    optionA: "A) To group multiple components together",
    optionB: "B) To provide a placeholder for dynamic content",
    optionC: "C) To avoid using unnecessary HTML elements when rendering",
    optionD: "D) To allow components to communicate with each other",
    answer: "optionC",
  },
  {
    prompt: "Q.14 What is Babel?",
    optionA: "A) A transpiler",
    optionB: "B) An interpreter",
    optionC: "C) A Compiler",
    optionD: "D) Both Compiler and Transpilar",
    answer: "optionD",
  }
];